Friends, many health
insurance products are
available in the market today.  Some influencer says
that you should take a policy of Rs 10 lakh,
give me a policy of Rs 20 lakh, take a policy of Rs 30 lakh, or Rs 50 lakh.
Insurance agents also
recommend it to their clients.  But do
you know which health insurance company will stand behind you when
you face a medical emergency, when you
need it
?   That
means your claim should be passed smoothly.
Suppose such an emergency
arises and you get hospitalized and
your cashless plan is rejected there.  5 lakh, 6 lakh, whatever
treatment is required, as a
patient, you are getting admitted in the hospital
and the claim is getting rejected there.
So how stressful the
situation will be at that time.  You
can think for yourself.  So friends, I have been working in the health insurance
industry for more than 16 years.
We have done a lot of claim
settlements.  So many
plans are also available in the market.  Out of them, I have
uploaded three such best health insurance in many other videos earlier.
You guys must have checked out.
But if you have to choose the best among them.
Three such health insurances which I have
filtered and brought for you.
If you watch this video, you
can at least take the best decision for yourself.  Friends,
without taking much time let's start the video.
Friends, if we talk about health
insurance, then the big health
insurance companies whose claim
settlement is the best.  So three I have
shortlisted are three health insurances.   The
first health insurance among these
is Optima Secure of HDFC Aego Health Insurance.
Next on the list is
ICICI LBR's Elevate Plan and the third one is
Bajaj General Insurance's Bajaj General My
Health Care Plan. Right, first of all, if
we see which company has the least number of
complaints, that means this company is smoothly
passing the claims of all its clients.
So, if we talk about HDFC's
HDFC Ago company, how many claims out of lakhs have
come against them, it is
1216 claims against them, that is, 12 to 16
claims have come against them.
Ok?  So if we talk about the ratio,
it is 8.64 ratio.  Talking about ICICI, the number of
claim complaints received by them per lakh
is 914, that is, their ratio is 3.15.  But this is the
ratio out of a lakh.  If we
talk about Bajaj Company, if we talk about Bajaj
General Insurance, then
they have received 511 lakh complaints.  So
friends, if we talk about their ratio here which
is 1.61, then if we talk about
HDFC Air, the ratio seems to be high here
but they have a large number of
clients, so it is very important for you to look at the client base also.
Now friends, if
we talk next, if we talk about their
claim ratio, that is, how much amount of money the
company has collected from the market and how much
claim amount they have
passed.  Meaning they have given the
price, if we talk about their claim ratio
friends HDFC Ago company has 81%, if
we talk about ICIC LBRD, theirs
is 79% and if we talk about Bajaj, it is 74%,
ideally if we talk about
denial claim ratio above 60 then it is
considered good and healthy because it is
necessary for the company to earn its profit also,
otherwise the company cannot sustain, right if
friends if we talk about
claim settlement ratio, the claim settlement
ratio of HDFC Air company
is 99%, it is a
very good claim settlement ratio, if we
talk about ICIC LBR, it is 97%, the
claim settlement ratio of Bajaj company is 96%,
so here if HDFC RO wins, that
is, their claim settlement ratio is
considered to be the best.  Next
friends, if we talk about solvency ratio, that is,
how many assets they have against their liabilities.  Right?  So
if we talk about HDFC Ago, theirs is 1.68,
if we talk about ICICI LBR, it is 2.68 and
Bajaj General Insurance, it is 3.49,
so ideally it is 1.5, basically
the IRD roll on IRD should be 1.5, right, so all
these three companies have above 1.5.  Now
friends let's talk about some unique points.
Suppose if we talk about any unique selling point, then
if we talk about HDFC
Algo Optima Secure, the
first point that comes here is A B C D.
That is, asthma, blood pressure, cholesterol
and diabetes.  You can cover it here,
you can cover it from 31 days.  Right?
So this is a plus point.  If we talk about
plus benefits.  Plus benefit is
that basically your Samshard will
increase by 50% every year and in two times
this Samsard becomes 100%.  Right.
Talking about the next benefit, they have
secure benefit.  That means if your SAM Assured in the first year is Rs
50 lakh,
your SAM Assured in the first year will become Rs 1
crore.  This means that on the very first day, your SAM ASH
gets doubled along with this secure benefit.
After that there is a restoration benefit.
All the companies are giving restoration benefits today.
Right?
You can take it along with the parent hood cover.
You can also cover maternity.  Next let's talk about
if there is a jump start here in the elite plan of ICIC LB, then
they have a jump
start.  Basically they have ABSITY and
they have jump start.  Like
hypertension, diabetes, obesity, asthma
and hyperlipidemia you can cover
from 31 days.  Right?  So
you can cover this jump start by paying an additional premium.
Power Booster: Power Booster is a very
big part.  In ICICI LT 11 plan.
What will happen here?  Basically, if
you add Power Booster rider, then your sum assured will become
100% every year i.e. double i.e. 100% as long as
you remain in the policy.
Due to inflation, your sum assured will keep increasing
every year. Another benefit is Infinity, that is,
you can avail the policy once in your lifetime for
infinite number of times.
Unlimited restoration is available in 11 plans of ICICI LB.
You must have already
known that the meaning of restoration is that
if you get exhausted, then the
company restores the same sum
assured without any extra charge.  Friends,
now let us talk about Bajaj General Insurance
's M Health Care Plan.
What is its unique selling point?
You will get OPD cover 200% off net premium.   You
can avail OPD cover of 200% of your net premium here.  Maternity waiting period
can be reduced to one year.  If there are
many companies in which the maternity waiting period is
4 years, 5 years, 7 years,
but here you can
reduce it to one year.  If we
talk about Bajaj's M Health Care Plan,
a facility of home nursing
is available here.  If your Samord is up to Rs 50 lakh
then you get Rs 1000 plus.
Nursing benefits are available here.
If we talk about SAMs above Rs 50 lakh, then
companies are
providing nursing benefits of more than Rs 10 lakh.  Right friends, now let's talk about
how much sum assured you can take.
If we talk about sum assured, here you will
see that if you take Optimal Secure plan,
then here you can take sum assured of Rs.
5 lakh, 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 50 lakh
and up to Rs. 2 crore. If
we talk about ICICI's Elite plan, then provision of Rs. 5
lakh, 7 lakh, 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 50 lakh, 3 crore and
unlimited sum
is available here, which you can take.  Talking about Bajaj General
Insurance My Health Care Plan,
you can avail insurance ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 5 crore.
Friends, if we
talk about the entry age, then
here we will see that in the Optimum Secure
Plan of HDFC Ergo, there is
no limit of 18 years.  So, if we look at all the three plans, there is no
limit on
entry age beyond 18 years.  Right?  Here, if we
talk about the policy tenure,
you can take a policy with tenure of one, two or three years in HDFC Air.
In Bajaj also, you
can take a policy with tenure of one, two or three years, in which if you take super for two years,
you get some additional discounts.
And if we talk about the limit plan of IC LBR,
you can purchase a policy with tenure of one, two, three or four years.
So if we talk about room rent here, there is
no capping on room rent in HDFC Air Optima Secure.  If
we talk about plan 11, here a single
private room is available.  There
is no such option like percentage etc. in this.  If we
talk about Bajaj, then single
private room is available here.  There is
no such provision of 1% or 2% here also.
So you can get a single private room
in both the plans.  So only in HDFC Air there is
no capping of room rates in any way.  Right?  Friends, now let
us move to the next slide, that is pre and
post hospitalization.  That is, how much do you get for the expenses incurred
before admission in the hospital and after discharge
?  So friends, if we talk about
pre and post, HDFC Algo Optima
Secure has 60 and 180 days.  It is of 60 pre
and 180 posts.  11 plans have 90 and
180 days.  It is 180 days.  It belongs to Bajaj.
Bajaj My Health Care Plan will have pre-paid plans.
Here, if we talk about pre, 30, 60,
90, 180 and post, 30, 60, 90,
180 and 240, then you can choose as per your convenience.
Next friends, if we talk about
modern treatment.  Friends, modern
treatment plays a very big role.   As
of today, all the surgeries are being done as per
modern technology in
which the time duration is less
and the success ratio is higher.  So if
we talk about HDFC Optima Secure has
up to the maximum modern treatment cover.  So there
is no capping in all three plans.  Up to the same amount modern
treatment is covered.  So this
is a big plus point that
modern treatment is 100% covered in all three plans.  So you please
check it.  If
modern treatment is not included in your policy then you
must think about it today itself.  If you have any such
problem then you can definitely contact us
on WhatsApp number.  So our
experts will guide you on what else
you have to do.  Friends, next if
we talk about e-consultation,
here in Optimus Secure
you get e-consultation for critical illness.
You can take ICICI LM Vid On.  Talking about Bajaj,
here you get unlimited e-consultation.  If you
ever have any disease, you
can take e-consultation.  You can contact the
doctors in their cashless penalty network.
Talking about ambulance, friends, there is
no limit on ambulance in all three plans.
Talking about air ambulance, here you have
hospitalization cover at Rs 5 lakh in Optima Secure.  If ICC Labrador has
emergency air ambulance cover.
If we look at Bajaj's M Health Care Plan, there is a sum
assured ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 1 crore in
which Rs 10 lakh is available.  And if the sum is above Rs
1 crore then you get air ambulance cover of Rs 20 lakh.
Annual Health Checkup Here
friends, if we talk about annual health
checkup, then in Optima Secure you will
get Rs. 500 per lakh, maximum up to Rs. 15000
right, if we talk about ICICI Labord, in this
you get 0.5% of the sum assured, the maximum you will get is Rs.
5000 right, you have to get any listed
test done, the annual
health checkup in Bajaj is covered here also, you
can take annual checkup, friends, next
if we talk about maternity cover, then if
you want any option of maternity cover, then you
can take it here, in Optima Secure
you can take it through a rider in
which there is parent food ride, in element plan there will be
10% of the basic sum assured and
after 2 years there will be maternity cover.
Talking about Bajaj, if the amount is between Rs 5 lakh to Rs 10
lakh, then you have a
maturity limit of Rs 50,000.  If the sum is Rs 15 to 20
lakh then the maturity limit is Rs 75,000.
If your income is between Rs 20 lakh to Rs 20
lakh or above, then
you can get maternity benefit of Rs 1 lakh here.
So friends, these were the top three health
insurance companies, if
we talk about fundamentals, if we talk about product features, then
these three companies are the
best health
insurance companies in the market today.  So friends, if we
talk about premium then it should
also be pocket friendly.  So here
if we compare all three
then whose premium is cheaper and if
you look at it with some add on features then which plan
is reliable for you?  So friends, if we
talk here, if we talk about HDFC
Aerogo, we have taken the example in which Rs 25
lakh is in front.  If there is a person of 40 years of age
who has two adult to child rights, then
here we have written that we have taken secure benefit.
If we take it with Secure Benefit, in
which you get 2X coverage i.e.
coverage from day one, here your 25 lakh becomes
50 lakh.  Ok?
Your consumable items are also covered here.
So the premium that is coming is Rs 38,959.
If you look at the premium a little, it is a little on the higher side.
Next, if we talk about ICICI LBRD's
11 plan, here also we have
taken an amount of Rs 25 lakh.  In which there is a person of 40 years.
Two Adult to Child is included in this policy.
In which we have taken no room rent capping.
We have taken the power booster.  Have
taken claim protector.  So here if we
talk about the premium, it is ₹33,923.
So the premium is
looking a little cheaper here in this plan.
Right?  Next friends, if
we talk about Bajaj's
plan, its Sameshwar is Rs 25 lakh.  He
is a 40 year old man with
two children, which we have already told you.   The
premium for which is coming is ₹4291.
So
if we look at the premium here, it is slightly
on the higher side.  But here
you can claim OPD of ₹80,000
for the year.  So this is an add on feature which is
available in this plan.  So
friends, you have to decide
which of the three plans is beneficial for you.  It
is beneficial for you.  If you
still have any confusion or doubts, you
can WhatsApp us.  Our team will help you to
provide your solutions.
So friends, if you like the video then
please like and share it.  If
you have not yet subscribed to the channel, do so
so that you will keep getting such latest videos in the future.  You will keep getting the
latest
information.  Every week we
upload two videos on our channel.  So that
our viewers can
take the best decision after watching them.  Ok friends, see you
in the next video.
Bye-bye till then.